# Samantha Knopper

samanthaknopper@hotmail.com | 0424 618 \*\*\* | Perth, Western Australia

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:samantha-knopper"><u>samantha-knopper</u></a> GitHub: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/Samw1s3"><u>https://github.com/Samw1s3</u></a> Portfolio:

https://samw1s3.github.io/portfoliosite/

Full stack web developer utilizing an education background to build a more engaging user experience on the web. Recently earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Western Australia, developed skills in HTML, JavaScript, CSS and responsive web design. Known as a methodical problem solver, with a passion for developing logical apps, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. With each project, my aim is to improve my designs and create more meaningful user experiences. I'm excited to employ my new skills in a quality-driven team environment, focused on building better experiences on the web.

# **Technical Skills**

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, AJAX

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Webpack

# **Projects**

Final project will start in 2 weeks.

Project Name | Repo | Deployed

Role in Project

- 1-liner What does the app do?
- 1-2 sentences on what the project accomplishes and your responsibilities
- Tools/Languages:

### Enviro Hub | Repo | Deployed

Developer

- Allows users to track their environmental habits and provides incentives for consistency
- EnviroHub allows users to track their environmental habits, becoming more consistent in their eco
  behaviours. I created the SQL database and used handlebars to make sure the correct information
  rendered in the required elements.
- Tools/Languages:
  - HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Handlebars, SQL ,API's
  - o Libraries (Multiavatar), BCRYPT,
  - o GitHub, VS Code, Heroku, Insomnia

### Awkward Turtle | Repo | Deployed

Project Manager / Developer

- Assists users in navigating awkward social situations
- This web app gives users advice on topics of conversations when interacting with new people in real life situations, as well as exit strategies when things go sideways. I was responsible for coordinating the different aspects to be completed by the team members, developed the apis for the weather report & activity suggestions and worked on the CSS.
- Tools/Languages:
  - HTML5, CSS, Javascript
  - o GitHub, VS Code

## **Work Experience**

### Adventist Schools Australia

July, 2014 - Dec, 2017 & Jan 2019 - Current

Classroom Teacher / Coordinator

Perth, Western Australia

- Leader I have been a year coordinator and currently am the learning support coordinator. I am able to support my team members, communicate our goals and make sure that all stakeholders were communicated with to make sure we all have the same expectations for events / activities.
- Solution Focused The current education environment has seen many problems arise, I have been heavily focused on finding solutions for my students and their teachers to assist with closing the gap between the students current levels and the curriculum standards.
- Collaborative I am required to work with all teachers at my current school with a variety of different tech skills, scaffolding instructions to allow them to implement new strategies. Meet regularly with stakeholders to make sure that we are all working together to move forward towards our goals

### Award:

- Benchmark Award, 2020
  - "Recognised your selfless contribution in nurturing our children the future of our nation"
  - Was selected due to innovation in using different technologies and tests to identify gaps in students learning to assist with learning support and academic acceleration.

## Colegio Panamericano

Aug, 2018 - Oct, 2018

Classroom Teacher (Maternity Leave Cover)

Bucaramanga, Colombia

- Adaptive Working in a new country and new students, I learnt a new curriculum and 3D printing software to allow my students to design and print their STEM projects. I was in charge of sharing this knowledge with my team teachers.
- Driven After many failed attempts of printing projects, I had to improve designs and processes to allow my students to successfully 3D print.

# Education

University of Western Australia, Western Australia Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Aug, 2022

Avondale College, New South Wales, Australia Bachelor of Education (primary)

Dec, 2009